《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我的先辈遭到了背叛  他们的功绩被抹除
My forefathers were betrayed, their legacy erased,
而我就是要惩罚那些背叛者
and I am here to punish those who wronged us
我们约好了的
We have a deal.
是的
We do.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 DustD   Silence   辰星晓Reginamoon   charcie   小酸奶!
翻译 大K   爵士年代蓬蓬裙   艾瑞卡   盐湖凉开水   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
我会不惜一切  天天训练
I'll do whatever it takes. I'll train every day.
这话你之前就说过
Yeah, well, you said that before, didn't you?
我愿意回学校
I'll even go back to school.
我救了你一命
I saved your life.
你也想杀了他
You wanted to do it, too.
只是没胆而已
You just didn't have the guts.
塞琳娜  我挺想你的
Selina... I miss you.
跟我们彩排的不一样
This is not what we rehearsed.
抱歉了  杰罗姆
I'm so sorry, Jerome.
英雄上场了
Enter the hero.
先生们
Gentlemen!
女士们  还有其他人
Ladies! Others!
我们探讨未来计划时能稍文明点吗
Let us discuss the future with a little civility, shall we?
所以说
So...
你们没一个知道是谁策划
not one of you knows who orchestrated
实施了阿卡姆劫狱
and/or executed the Arkham breakout?
我觉得这难以置信
I find that hard to believe.
警察的唯一线索
I mean, the cops' only lead
是个老瞎子  我的天
is an old blind man, for God's sake.
一个瞎子
A blind man!
那在座的谁才值得信任
Then who here is to be trusted?
因为有人知道内情
Because someone knows.
我们以为是你
We thought it was you.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
我们本来好的不得了
We've never had it better.
我给了你们最大限度的自由
I gave you all of the freedom in the world
生意也蒸蒸日上
and business boomed.
我们所有人都是
For all of us.
崭新的一代
A new generation.
结果那个红发疯子毁了一切
Then that ginger maniac had to spoil everything.
即便他现在已经死了
Even now he's dead,
民众还是余惊未定
the public is still terrified,
生意止步不前  我们却在干什么
business is in the can and what are we doing?
自己窝里斗
Fighting among ourselves.
你们就想这么过下去吗
Is this how any of us want to live?
争执不休
Squabbling, brawling,
东躲西藏吗
running, hiding?
这座城市现在是我们的了
This city belongs to us now.
随之而来的还有责任
But kids, that brings responsibilities.
我们需要重塑品牌形象
We need to restore confidence in our brand, if you will.
我们需要秩序和团结  懂了吗
We need discipline and unity, yes?
不许再混乱不堪
There will be no more chaos.
不许再帮派斗争
No more gang wars.
不许再街头血斗
No more blood in the streets,
吓到平民百姓
scaring decent folk.
从现在开始  你要想杀谁
From now on, if you want to kill someone,
勒索谁  偷谁的东西或者绑架谁
blackmail, steal or kidnap anyone,
都要先跟我汇报
I need to hear about it first.
懂了吗
Understand?
-明白了  -嗯
- Yeah, got it. - Yeah.
-好的  -嗯
- Fine. - Yeah.
老板  有人...
Boss, there's somebody...
真精彩
Bravo.
很有所罗门王的派头
Quite the King Solomon.
你把他们调教得不错
You had them nicely in line.
你是谁
Who are you?
我哥哥很想和你聊聊
My brother would very much like to talk to you.
单独聊
Alone.
你干吗那样看我
Why you looking at me like that?
你又不认识我
You don't know me.
放松  布奇
Relax, Butch.
他脾气不好
He has issues.
躁郁症
Bipolar.
我只是说她又不认识我
She don't know me, I'm just saying.
你哥哥
Your brother?
西奥多·盖勒文
Theodore Galavan.
外边有车等着你
There's a car waiting for you outside.
我受够了你这小圣母了  戈登
I'm sick and tired of your holier-than-thou crap, Gordon!
是吗  那就拿出点警察的样子
Yeah? Then do some police work.
你上一个逮捕的人是你的赌马经纪人
Last arrest you made was your bookie.
我是纳撒尼尔·巴恩斯
My name is Nathaniel Barnes.
纳撒尼尔·巴恩斯警监
Captain Nathaniel Barnes.
没错
That's right.
我是你们的新上司
I'm your new boss.
立正
Ten-hut!
你
You.
给打扫干净了
Clean that up.
你们知道这警局什么时候建的吗
You know when this place was built?
是一百多年前
Over 100 years ago.
你们能想象那之后
Can you imagine how many perps
这里关过多少罪犯吗
have been booked in here since that time?
关过多少杀人犯
All the murderers, rapists,
强奸犯  小偷
thieves that have been locked up?
他们再建不出这样的楼了
They don't make 'em like this anymore--
坚实  稳固
strong, sturdy.
但是
And yet...
就在不久前
just days ago,
一个逃犯就那么闯进来
an escaped convict just strolls in here,
闯进咱们的地盘
into our house-- our house--
杀了你们的局长
and murders your commissioner
连同你们九位战友
and nine of your fellow comrades.
我当时不在场都感到羞愧
I wasn't even here and I'm ashamed.
你们不感到羞愧吗
Are you all ashamed?
我希望有
I hope so.
在这里却不感到羞愧
Anyone that's here that's not ashamed,
或是愤怒的人
and angry,
都应该辞职
should resign.
立刻辞职
Right now.
你们中有些人在自欺欺人
Some of you are lying to yourselves.
我手里有你们的资料
I've got your files here.
我全部都看过了
I've read them all.
叫到名字的站出来
Step forward if you hear your name called.
波拉德
Pollard.
格思里
Guthrie.
科尔森
Coulson.
道勒
Dowler.
布鲁克斯
Brooks.
佩雷斯
Perez.
海托华
Hightower.
你们并没感到羞愧
You aren't ashamed.
因为你们没有羞耻心
You have no shame.
你们不是警察
You're not police,
你们是渣滓罪犯
you're low-life criminals.
受贿
Bribery,
药物滥用
drug abuse,
勒索  敲诈
extortion, racketeering...
一群混蛋
Sons of bitches!
你们全都被解雇了
You're all fired!
出去时
Drop off your badges
把你们的警徽和配枪交给接待警员
and your guns with the desk sergeant on your way out.
你不能这么做  我们有人权
You can do this! We got rights!
说得对
Yes, you're right.
你的确有人权
You do have rights.
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你有权请律师
You have the right to an attorney.
带他走
Take him.
从现在起
From now on...
任何一名警官
any officer,
警探  新人或是职员  只要触犯了法律
detective, rookie or clerk who breaks the law
不仅饭碗不保
will not just lose their job,
还要被关起来
they will go to jail.
如果有谁对犯罪视若无睹
If you turn a blind eye to crime,
我会逮捕你
I will bust you.
如果因为怯懦或冷漠
If you fail to help a fellow officer
而没有协助你的战友
because of cowardice or apathy,
我也会逮捕你
I will bust you!
你们还站在这里干什么
What the hell are you still doing here?
别逼我发火
Don't make me mad.
没听到自己名字的人
Anyone who didn't hear their name called,
回去工作
get back to work.
请来我办公室一趟
I'd like to see you in my office, please.
觉得我刚刚在大厅说的那番话如何
Well, what do you think about what I said out there?
我同意您的每一句话  长官
I agree with every word, sir.
每一句话吗
Every word, huh?
你是个马屁精吗  戈登
You a sycophant, Gordon?
不是  长官
No, sir.
"No, sir."
我看过你的档案
I've read all your files.
军队  警校  哥谭市警局
Army, Academy, GCPD.
你是个惹事精
You're a troublemaker.
是个斗士
A fighter.
这样评价你是否准确
Is that an accurate assessment?
准确  长官
Yes, sir.
很好
Good.
你就是我的副手了
You're my second in command.
现在开始  吉姆
Starting now, Jim,
我们要整治这个警局
we're gonna fix this department
让这座城市再次敬畏法律和秩序
and bring respect for law and order back to this city.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
我们...
We're, uh...
有点人手不够
kind of shorthanded.
怎么  你觉得我炒的人太多了吗
What, you think I cut too deep?
你可以再炒20个都不算多
You could have thrown out 20 more guys and not hit bottom.
整治这间警局会是场硬仗
Fixing this department's gonna be tough.
也许会比您想的更困难
Maybe tougher than you think...
长官
sir.
欢迎来到我的队伍
Welcome to my unit,
你个苦着脸的兵蛋子
you sad-ass Army hump.
困难于我们而言不过是家常小菜
Tough is what we eat for breakfast.
您是海军陆战队啊
A jarhead, huh?
谁能想到呢
Who would've guessed?
长官
Sir.
我希望你刚和他说了他犯了个大错
I hope you just told him he made a huge mistake.
我不觉得他犯了错
I don't think he did.
拜托  吉姆  我们见过他这类人
Come on, Jim, we've seen his type,
来来去去的  理想主义者
come and go, idealists,
做事只想走直线
always looking to walk the straight line --
哥谭没有直路
Gotham doesn't have straight lines,
只有迂回曲折和死路
it's got twists and turns and dead ends.
没错  但不是一定非要那样
Yeah. But it doesn't have to be that way.
詹姆斯市长仍然不见踪影
With Mayor James still missing
而副市长近日也被杀害
and the deputy mayor recently murdered,
为市政府选出一个领导
the need for leadership at City Hall
是哥谭市民最为关心的问题
is of paramount concern to Gotham's citizens.
今天  又有两名候选人
Today, two more hopeful candidates
宣布参加竞选
have thrown their hats into the ring.
詹妮丝·考菲尔德是一名市议员
Janice Caulfield is a city councillor
她是作为环保斗士开始了政治生涯
who began her political career as an environmental activist.
兰德尔·霍布斯
Randall Hobbs--
哥谭历史上任职最长的工会主席
the longest-serving teamster boss in Gotham's history,
也是一位拥有广泛群众基础的候选人
is another candidate with a strong base.
不过最新民调显示  一位尚未宣布参选的市民
In the latest polls, though, a surprise surge for a man
得到了意外高的支持率
who has not even declared his candidacy--
那就是西奥·盖勒文
Theo Galavan.
据发言人透露
The dashing billionaire businessman
这位帅气的亿万富商
has not ruled out a bid for the mayor's job,
尚未否定参选可能
but he is considering his options,
不过他正在考虑当中
according to a spokesman.
科波特先生  终于见面了
Mr. Cobblepot, finally we meet.
叫我企鹅就行了
Call me Penguin.
我听说你讨厌那个名字
I thought I heard you hated that name.
已经不讨厌了
It grew on me.
那就叫企鹅了
Penguin, it is.
请吧  坐
Please, sit.
你的头怎么样了
How's your head?
康复中  谢谢你
Healing, thank you.
真把我吓得不轻
Gave me quite a scare.
你真幸运  能活着出来
You were lucky to get out of there with your life.
还真是
Wasn't I just.
是凭运气吗
Was it luck?
你是个聪明人
You are a clever man.
时机刚好  亲爱的
Perfect timing, dear.
你俩认识吧
Do you two know each other?
见过面
We've met.
我的天
Oh, my.
阿卡姆劫狱
The Arkham breakout,
哥谭市警局屠杀
the GCPD massacre,
杰罗姆和疯子帮
Jerome and the Maniax.
都是你搞得鬼
All you.
当然了
Of course.
正是我
Guilty.
我真不该
It was foolish of me to think
以为能骗过"哥谭之王"
I could trick the "The King of Gotham."
给你
Here.
你比我更需要
You need this more than me.
我再弄一杯
I'll make another.
我妹妹说你管理你的新帝国
My sister tells me you're doing a stellar job
很有一套
of organizing your new empire.
尽力罢了
I try.
你才不是"哥谭之王"
You're not "The King of Gotham."
你是"垃圾之王"
You're "The King of Garbage."
一年前  我还只是给菲什·穆尼打伞的
A year ago, I held Fish Mooney's umbrella.
现在她已死在我手上
Now she's dead by my hand.
还有马罗尼
Along with Maroni.
法尔科内躲了起来
Falcone is in hiding,
他们的生意都已归我
and all of their businesses are mine.
他们都低估了我
They all underestimated me.
我建议你不要犯同样的错误
I suggest you not make the same mistake.
我妹妹太直了
My sister is too blunt.
但她说的是实话
But she is honest.
两百年前  一群人呕心沥血才建立起
The foundations of this great city were laid 200 years ago,
这座伟大城市的基石
by some very dedicated people.
现在  这只是一个满是人渣
Now it's an old crumbling pigsty,
分崩离析的猪圈
full of human waste.
该迈入未来了
It's time to move into the future.
一个更干净  更明亮的...
A cleaner, brighter...
未来
future.
那片都是居住区
Those are all residential areas,
这样不是会毁掉上千人的家吗
so thousands of homes would have to be destroyed, wouldn't they?
是啊  怎么了
Yeah. So?
困难在于
Here's the rub:
要重建  就得先摧毁
in order to rebuild, I need first to destroy,
但是我不能这么做
but I can't do that.
你看看新闻  我可是英雄
I mean, watch the news, I'm a hero.
但是你在这种事上可谓天赋异禀
But you have a certain flair for such a task.
你  企鹅
You, Penguin...
你会成为我的毁灭者
you will be my destroyer.
我真是受宠若惊
Truly, I'm flattered.
非常感谢你能想到我  但是...
Thank you so much for thinking of me, but...
尊敬的先生  你完全看错我了
my dear sir, you have me all wrong.
我没有毁灭的天赋
I have no flair for destruction.
我是一名建造者  我解决问题
I'm a builder, a problem solver.
再说了  这么庞大的工程需要取得
Besides, such a huge project would need the support
上百名市政官员的支持
of hundreds of city officials.
是啊  只有最高层的人才能好好完成此事
Yes, only the highest authority could see it through correctly.
比如  压倒性获胜的市长
Say, a mayor with a landslide mandate.
但你不是候选人
But you're not a candidate.
我会成为候选人的
Oh, I will be.
而且是顺应民意
By popular demand.
但是  一些其他候选人
Alas, some of my fellow candidates
还是有可能赢下这场选举的
actually stand a chance of winning,
所以他们必须消失
so they'll have to go.
消失
Go?
我需要你也对我下手
And I'm gonna need you to take a crack at me also.
当然你得失手
And miss, of course.
我可不希望别人觉得
Don't want anyone to think that...
我跟其他候选人的死有关系
I had anything to do with my fellow candidates' demise.
詹妮丝·考菲尔德竞选市长
请投给霍布斯
这招很聪明
That's smart thinking.
但是恕我直言  盖勒文先生
However, with all due respect, Mr. Galavan,
你找错人了
I'm not your man.
你需要的是一个杀手
You need an assassin.
在哥谭  你在电话簿上就能找到杀手的电话
This is Gotham, you can find them in the phone book.
就在字母A下面
Under "A."
请等一下  企鹅先生
One moment, Mr. Penguin.
不好意思  我还以为你是个有远见的人
I'm sorry, I took you for a man of vision.
你去拿遥控器好吗  塔比莎亲爱的
Tabitha, you want to get the remote, dear?
好啊
Yay.
在你离开前
Before you leave,
我妹妹想给你看看
my sister would love to show you
她最喜欢的真人秀
her favorite reality show.
她简直看上瘾了
She's addicted.
她现在有点闷
She's being kind of dull right now,
但有时候她会哭叫着撞门呢
but sometimes she cries and bangs on the door.
-求求你  -母亲
- Please. - Mother.
我发誓  我不知道
I swear, I swear, I don't know about this.
你们会付出代价的
You'll pay for this.
这就对了
That's the spirit.
这些人死了  你母亲就可以活
They die, your mother lives.
很简单
Simple.
求求你
Please!
我发誓  我什么都不知道
I swear, I swear, I don't know nothing...
哥谭
第二季  第四集
这里是汤普金斯
Thompkins.
早上好  汤普金斯医生
Good morning, Dr. Thompkins.
巴恩斯警监  哥谭市警局
Captain Barnes, GCPD.
巴恩斯警监
Captain Barnes.
我听到你不少好话  医生
I hear great things about you, Doc.
准备忙起来吧
Get ready to get real busy.
我们会给你送去一大批坏人的尸体
We're gonna be sending you a whole lot of dead bad guys.
好啊
Okay-okay.
让吉姆接电话好吗
May I speak to Jim?
他要跟你说话
He wants to talk to you.
我是戈登
This is Gordon.
7点钟去警校等我
Meet me at the police academy at 0700.
警校  是  长官
The academy, yes, sir.
不介意的话  长官  您怎么...
If you don't mind me asking, sir...
大家都知道你跟法医有一腿
Everybody knows you're banging the M.E.
一个小时后见
See you in an hour.
班上年龄最大的学生
Oldest in your class.
不是最壮的  也不是最快的
Not the strongest or the fastest
甚至也不是最聪明的
or even the most academically gifted either,
然而  却以全班第一名毕业
and yet... you finished at the top of your class.
你是怎么做到的呢
Now how did you do that?
让我来告诉你
I'll tell you how.
因为你是一名战士
You were a soldier.
你的同学
You saw combat
还窝在家中地下室里打飞机时
while your classmates were still playing with themselves
你已上过战场
in their parents' basements.
你已身染鲜血
You got blood on your face.
可以这么说吧
You could say that.
你是一名勇士  吉姆
You're a warrior, Jim.
我也是
So am I.
但你以往的行事风格行不通了
But you can't carry on the way you've been,
不能再单枪匹马去应战了
going after everyone on your own.
你需要靠谱的帮手
You need help that you can rely on.
恕我直言  长官...
With all due respect, sir...
要是找群未被收买的年轻警察组建支队伍呢
What if there were a team of young cops who haven't been bought yet?
个个生龙活虎  作风端正
Not jaded, not corrupted.
仍对司法系统满怀希望与信念
Still filled with hope and faith in the system.
警校学员
Cadets.
这是全国最优秀的警校
This is the greatest academy in the country.
下周就毕业典礼了
Graduation is next week.
我们可以在其他分局糟蹋他们之前
We could grab a group of their finest
挑出几个最出色的学员
before some precinct kills their spirit.
去看看也无妨吧
Wouldn't hurt to look into it, right?
古斯
Gus.
巴恩斯警监
Captain Barnes.
这是戈登
This is Gordon.
认识  我记得这家伙
Sure, I remember this guy.
他很喜欢还嘴
He argued a lot.
我觉得我只是好问
I'd like to think I was raising questions.
有人选吗
What do you got for us?
这边请
This way.
留意那个小丫头
Keep your eye on the little one.
被人揍得不轻的那个吗
The one getting her ass handed to her?
急什么
Wait.
耐心啊
Patience.
要是我没记错
Not your strong virtue,
这不是你的强项  戈登
if I remember right, Gordon.
州摔跤冠军
State wrestling champ,
警校跑卫
academy running back.
为什么考进这里  不拿体育奖学金上大学
Why this place and not a sports scholarship?
我们街区的孩子拿不到奖学金
People from my neighborhood don't get scholarships.
他们加入黑帮  贩毒
They join gangs, sell drugs.
我需要改变我的人生方向
I needed to change the direction my life was going.
马丁纳兹先生
Mr. Martinez...
资料显示你是警校最佳枪手
says here you're the best shot this school's ever seen.
你在哪里学的射击
Where'd you learn to shoot?
哥谭射击场
Gotham gun range.
我妈妈的三份工作之一就是在那儿当清洁工
One of my mother's three jobs was cleaning it.
她去世后
When she died,
场主允许我下班后去那练习
the owner let me go there after hours and practice,
直到我发泄完我的愤怒
until I worked out my anger.
我现在还去
I still go there.
你的智商来这里可惜了  加勒特
You're way too smart to be here, Garrett.
让我猜猜
Don't tell me--
你父亲是警察吧
your father's a cop.
不是
Negative.
我父亲的家族生意被武装暴徒毁了
My father's family business was destroyed by armed thugs
因为他们要他交保护费
who demanded he pay them protection money.
他拒绝后
When he refused,
被他们打了个半死
they beat him half to death.
我来这里是为了确保这种事不再发生
I'm here to make sure that doesn't ever happen again.
加勒特
Garrett!
平克尼
Pinkney!
乔茜
Josie!
马丁纳兹
Martinez!
你们发誓以生命捍卫警徽的尊严吗
You swear to honor that badge with your life?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你们现在是哥谭市警局
You are now Unit Alpha
第一突击队的成员了
of the GCPD Strike Force
听从詹姆斯·戈登警探的命令
under the command of Detective James Gordon.
你们只对他负责  而他直接对我负责
You answer only to him, and him only to me.
解散
Dismissed.
突击队
Strike force?
挺威风的  是吧
Got a nice ring to it, doesn't it?
他们都是好孩子
They're good kids.
但是这么年轻就去面对外面的世界
But facing what's out there at their age?
这有很大风险  长官
That's a big risk, sir.
确实
True.
但我们还有什么顾虑呢
What do we got to lose?
是  长官
Yes, sir.
在巨大动乱面前
For your acts of courage
你表现出了英勇
in the face of overwhelming uncertainty,
为了表示对你的肯定
the city of Gotham would like to give you
哥谭市现授予你
this token of appreciation.
勇气勋章
The Medal of Valor and Bravery.
盖勒文先生
Mr. Galavan.
请不要见外  叫我西奥
Uh, please-- Theo.
西奥  老天啊
Theo, for Pete's sake,
您为什么不竞选市长呢
why aren't you running for mayor?
趴下
Get down!
大家都原地别动
Everybody stay where you are!
大家都好吗
Everyone okay?
没人受伤吧
Everyone?
知道吗
You know what?
哥谭人民不会因重压而退缩
Gothamites don't buckle under pressure,
我也不会
and neither will I.
这些渣滓想毁掉哥谭这座伟大的城市
We will not be intimidated by the scum
但我们不会被他们吓倒
that seek to reduce this great city of Gotham to ruins.
如果坏人想要阻止我竞选
If the bad guys want to stop me running,
那我想我也别无选择了
well, then I guess I got no choice.
我会竞选市长一职
I will run for mayor.
好啊
Yes!
市长候选人考菲尔德办公室
Hello, Caulfield for Mayor.
好的  好的
Yes, uh... will do!
抱歉  你们不能进去
Excuse me, you can't go in there.
考菲尔德女士  很高兴见到你
Miss Caulfield, what a pleasure.
请允许我做个自我介绍
Allow me to introduce myself.
我知道你是什么人
I can see what you are.
你怎么进来的
How did you get in?
我知道现在很晚了
I know it's late,
但此事刻不容缓
but I'm afraid there's no time for delay.
今早有人想杀西奥·盖勒文
Someone tried to kill Theo Galavan this morning.
你是来杀我的吗
Are you here to kill me?
是的
Actually, yes.
求你了  不要
Please, no.
我是位母亲
I'm a mother.
-等等  -我也有母亲
- Wait! - I have a mother, too.
站稳了  伙计们
Steady now, folks.
想想蓝天和玉米地
Just think of blue skies and cornfields.
我就这样
That's what I do.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing this?
亲爱的  我也不知道
Darling, I got no freaking idea.
我们成天都干些疯事
We've been doing crazy stuff all day long.
好了  我们走了  抱歉把你们今晚搅和了
Well, we're away then. Sorry to ruin your evening.
记住了
Now, remember...
好了
Yeah.
我有你们的姓名和住址了
I got your names and addresses.
想想家人  闭紧嘴巴  好吗
So think about your families and keep mum, eh?
在等什么人吗
Are you waiting for someone?
没有
No.
那是你的工作
That's your job.
这是为了雷吉
That's for Reggie.
我知道是你杀了他
I know you killed him.
我不知道你想从布鲁斯少爷这儿得到什么
Now, I don't know what you want with Master Bruce,
但我确定
but I'm certain
没有你  他能过得更好
that his life's gonna be a damn sight better without you in it.
你给自己行行好  小妞
So you do yourself a favor, treacle,
滚蛋吧
and jog on.
好啊
All good.
布鲁斯少爷
Oh, Master Bruce.
如果你愿意  我可以开到前门去
You know, I could always pull out front, if you want.
不了
No, uh,
阿尔弗雷德  我不想其他孩子看到
Alfred, I don't want the other kids to see...
你有个管家
To see that you've got a butler.
嗯  我完全理解
Yeah, I completely understand that.
我按你说的预约了明晚的晚餐
I made dinner reservations, as requested, for tomorrow night.
盖勒文先生提议去君威酒店
Mr. Galavan suggested the Regal Hotel.
挺高档的
It's very posh.
得花不少的钱了
You're gonna be forking out serious dosh for that, I'll tell you.
他救了我一命
He saved my life.
请他吃顿饭不算什么
Dinner's the least I can do to repay him.
布鲁斯少爷
Uh, Master Bruce,
你去哪
where are you going?
我算了  韦恩庄园离这里有6.5英里
Now, I clocked Wayne Manor at exactly six and a half miles.
90分钟到两小时内应该能到
It should take 90 minutes to two hours,
当然了  这要看你中间停下来几次
depending on how many times you stop, of course.
是你说你想训练的
Now, you said you wanted to train.
做好准备
To prepare.
训练吧
Well, this is it.
等等  你
Wait, you...
你要我走回去吗
you expect me to-to walk?
不  布鲁斯少爷
No, Master Bruce.
我要你跑回去
I expect you to run.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle,
自从我第一次见到你
ever since I first laid eyes on you,
我就感到与你心有灵犀
I've felt this deep connection.
或许你也有同感
Perhaps you've felt it, too?
俗死了
How cheesy.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle,
你或许早已感觉到了我的爱慕
you've perhaps felt my affections from afar.
"早已"  不是吧  天呐
"Afar"? Really? Oh, God.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle...
闭嘴
Be quiet.
我不需要你评头论足
I don't need your opinion.
你需要别再嘟嘟囔囔
What you need is to stop mumbling
畏手畏脚  直接告诉她你的想法
and fumbling and tell her what's up.
她一直被人欺负  不被珍惜
Well, she's been bullied and taken for granted for too long.
我希望她明白
And I want her to understand...
你救了她一命
You saved her life!
老天爷啊
For God's sake!
她欠你的
She owes you.
这是你应得的
Take what you deserve.
柯林格小姐
Miss Kringle.
今晚  一起吃饭
Dinner, tonight.
来我家  8点
Chez Moi. 8:00.
好
Okay.
那好啊
I'd like that.
的确会很好
You will.
一个明智的警察曾说
A wise cop once said,
如果你逮到个砸窗户的小孩
if you catch a kid smashing a window,
哪怕他很小  也得抓他
even a small one, bust him.
你放过他  他会再去砸别的窗子
You let it slide, and he'll smash another one.
然后他会涂鸦墙壁  偷自行车
Then he'll tag a wall, steal a bike,
打劫商店  或许抢劫
rob a store, maybe hold someone up.
不惩罚犯罪也是一种犯罪
Crime unpunished is a crime in itself.
这座城市在流血致死
This city is bleeding to death
就因为我们老是放过罪犯
from the amount of free passes we hand out.
该给伤口止血了
Time to put a tourniquet over that wound.
今后起
From now on...
再不得放过任何人
no one gets a free pass.
这个突击队是做什么的
What is this strike force for?
发出一个信号  这无法无天的传染病
To send a message that this epidemic of lawlessness
将不再肆意蔓延
will no longer be treated
而是会被消灭
but extinguished.
不讲一点情面
With extreme prejudice.
先生们  女士
Gentlemen, lady,
这是你们的新制服
your new uniforms.
长官  有人打来电话
Sir, got a caller.
说考菲尔德议员遭人袭击
Says Councillor Caulfield has been attacked.
她死了
Says she's dead.
没有监控
No security cameras.
先是盖勒文  然后是她
Galavan and now her.
看来是计划作案
Looks like a damn pattern.
但她死了
Only she's dead.
行了  各位
Come on, people!
谁知道什么
Who knows what?
给我们个名字  描述
Just give us a name, a description.
你们不用作证
You will not have to testify.
他们知道我们的名字和地址
They have our names and addresses.
考菲尔德女士被捅了数刀
Ms. Caulfield was stabbed repeatedly.
可能淹死在了自己的血泊中
Probably drowned in her own blood.
算了  吉姆
Forget it, Jim.
持刀的那人
The man with the knife
身材矮小
was short,
衣着华丽
fancy clothes.
走路姿势奇怪
Walked funny.
盖勒文先生
Ah, Mr. Galavan.
谢谢你来见我
Thank you for meeting me.
很荣幸  你客气了
It's an honor. The pleasure's all mine.
我们大堂见了  布鲁斯少爷
I'll meet you in the lobby, Master Bruce.
-一起吃吧  -客气了  先生
- Oh, why not dine with us? - That's very kind of you, sir,
但那样不太合适
but I don't think it's appropriate.
而且我知道布鲁斯少爷有话想单独跟你讲
And I know that Master Bruce wants to speak to you on his own.
少爷
Sir.
谢谢  阿尔弗雷德
Thanks, Alfred.
慢用
Enjoy.
你喜欢这里吗
You like this place?
我没来过这儿
I've never been here before.
老实说  我不怎么出来
To be honest, I don't...go out much.
希望我能改变这点
Well, I hope I can change that.
我肯定总能找到什么无聊的活动拉你参加
There's always some tedious function I could drag you to.
我就是想借此机会感谢你
I just...I wanted this opportunity to thank you,
亲口感谢你救了我
in person, for saving my life.
你太客气了
Oh, you're very kind.
老实说  我都不知道自己是怎么了
The truth is, I don't know what came over me.
我觉得我脑子当时都不听使唤了
I-I don't think I was in complete control of my faculties.
我也想跟你
I also wanted to speak with you
面对面谈谈
face-to-face.
是关于你父母之死的
It's regarding your parents' passing.
我觉得难以置信  这么久了
I find it astonishing that the police have failed
警方竟没找到任何证据或真正的疑犯
to produce any evidence or any real suspect in all this time.
的确令人失望
It is disappointing.
甚至你父亲自己的公司
Even your father's own company,
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises,
也完全没能推进调查
has failed to advance the investigation in any way.
真是令人震惊
It's shocking.
是啊  盖勒文先生
Yes, Mr. Galavan,
的确令人失望
it's-it's very disappointing.
那是茜尔薇
That's Silver.
什么
Uh, I'm sorry?
茜尔薇·圣克劳德
Silver St. Cloud.
她父亲是我的继兄
Her father was my stepbrother.
很不幸  他过世了
He passed, sadly.
她现在是我的养女
She's my ward now.
你想见见她吗
Would you like to meet her?
好
Yes.
你好  亲爱的
Hello, my dear.
叔叔
Uncle.
给你介绍一下  这是布鲁斯·韦恩
I'd like to introduce you to Bruce Wayne.
认识你很高兴  布鲁斯
Nice to meet you, Bruce.
你好
Hello.
我来早了  就来外面玩玩
I was early, so I came out here.
今天好暖和
It's such a warm day.
知道吗
Do you know,
你俩应该很快就是同校同学了
I do believe that you two will be sharing a school soon.
安德斯预科学校  是吧
Anders Prep, yes?
茜尔薇在国外待了两年  这才刚回来
Silver just got back to, uh, Gotham after two years abroad.
是瑞士
Switzerland.
日内瓦
Geneva.
嗯  我们在那儿有栋房子
Yes. We have a house there.
那里什么样
So, what's it like?
瑞士吗
Switzerland?
不  学校啊  傻瓜
No. Prep, silly.
还行吧
I think it's fine.
我这一阵一直在家上学
I've been homeschooling for quite a while now,
所以我基本上也是新学生
so I'm virtually a new boy, too.
那我们就一起勇敢面对了
Then we shall brave it together.
来我家
我以为是家餐厅呢
I was kind of expecting a restaurant.
来我家
柯林格小姐  真抱歉
Miss Kringle, I'm so sorry. I-I'm sorry.
我是该说清楚的
I should have been more clear.
我喜欢做饭
I like to cook.
我是个好厨子  没事吧
I'm a good cook. Is that okay?
没事
It is. It is. Um, and...
或许你该喊我柯丽丝汀
perhaps you should call me Kristen.
柯丽丝汀
Kristen.
霍布斯的竞选办公室占了整个二层楼
Hobbs' campaign office is the entire second floor.
你真要这么做吗
You sure about this?
别担心  我有把握
Don't worry. I've got it under control.
好吧  你得告诉我究竟是怎么回事
Okay, you gotta tell me what the hell's going on.
我知道你说什么我就得做什么
I know I gotta do whatever you say,
但至少告诉我我们为什么要这么做
but at least tell me why the hell we're doing it.
他们抓了我妈妈  布奇
They have my mother, Butch.
谁
Who?
盖勒文和他妹妹
Galavan and his sister.
他们抓了她
They have her.
是他们逼我这么做
They're making me do this.
老天爷
Holy smokes.
我们得找到你妈妈
We gotta find your mom.
如果他们知道我们在找她  他们会伤害她的
If they find out we're looking, they'll hurt her.
别担心  我们会找到她的
Don't worry. We'll find her.
他来了
He's here.
行动吧
Let's go.
好的
Got it.
谢谢
Thanks.
我还是认为我们该把你转移到更安全的地方
I still think we should move you somewhere a little more secure.
算了  有胆来杀我的人
Forget it. Anyone has the guts to come after me--
会很快明白他们惹的是什么样的人
they'll find out real soon who they're messin' with.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
我是志愿者
I came here to volunteer.
滚回雇你的人那儿去吧
Well, run back to whoever hired you.
告诉他们我不会退缩的
Tell them I'm not going anywhere.
这个城市需要我
This city needs me.
胸牌不错啊
Cool pins.
数数吧  白痴
Count, idiot.
-我们有五个人  -我知道
- There's five of us. - I know.
太不公平了
Hardly seems fair.
快跑  快走
Move, move, move, move, move! Go!
别停下
Keep going!
好了  快走
There you go. Right there!
快走
Go!
哥谭市警局  放下武器
GCPD! Put down your weapons!
散开  两边夹击
Fan out! Flank him from both sides,
交火压制他
catch him in our crossfire.
嗯  去吧
Yeah, do that.
我掩护你们  上
I'll cover you. Go!
好吧  他们动作挺麻利
Okay. So they move well.
没想到啊
Unexpected.
上上上
Move! Move, move, move!
走吧
Let's go!
枪手逃了  长官
Shooter got away, sir.
那人是维克多·萨斯
You just met Victor Zsasz.
他如今为企鹅工作了
Works for Penguin these days.
企鹅在玩什么把戏
What the hell is Penguin playing at?
我觉得我欠你个道歉
Not, but I... I feel like, um, I owe you an apology.
我觉得我一直对你态度很坏
I feel as though I have been nothing but mean to you.
我觉得不能这么说
No, I don't think that's fair.
我觉得我一直在骚扰你
I feel like all I've ever done is... is annoy you.
我老是做些不合适的事
I've been consistently inappropriate.
不不  是我
No. No, no, no, no, it's me.
你一直很贴心
You have been nothing but sweet,
是我无视你的卡片  你的礼物
and I ignored your card and your... your gift.
柯林格小姐  老实说
Miss Kringle, I can honestly say
我们的互动总是我一天最美好的时刻
that our interactions are always the highlight of my day.
叫我柯丽丝汀
Please. Uh... Kristen.
天呐  我甚至还说是你
Oh, my, God, I even accused you
写了多尔蒂的道别信
of writing Dougherty's good-bye note.
是啊
Right.
-疯了  -谁知道那混蛋怎么想的
- Crazy. - I mean, oh... who knows what that jerk was thinking?
-是混蛋  -我怎么能允许他碰我
- Jerk. - How I ever let him lay a hand on me,
真是不可思议
I'll never know.
他死了我高兴
I'm glad he's dead.
他...
Well, he's...
他只是离开了这里
he just left town.
他没...死
He's not... dead.
嗯  是啊  我知道
Right, yeah, I know.
就是个说法
Figure of speech.
他对你而言与死无异了
He's dead to you.
滚出你的生活了  不是真死了
Out of your life. Not dead, dead.
我去下洗手间
I'm gonna use the restroom.
你搞砸了  白痴  干得好
You blew it, dummy. Nice work.
-别烦我  -你是跟我说话吗
- Leave me alone! - Are you talking to me?
不是
No.
真的  柯丽丝汀  不是说你
Honestly, Kristen, I wasn't talking to you.
那还有谁啊
Who else is there?
我是在跟...自己说话
I talk... to myself.
我知道  很疯狂  我就是...
It's crazy, I know. I just, I have this, um...
我脑子里有个声音
I have this voice inside my head,
算是一个更强势的我
a sort of stronger version of me,
他管束这个笨拙的我
that keeps this me in line, because I'm such a klutz.
我能理解
I can understand that.
我觉得我们都能听到这样的声音
I think that we all have a voice like that.
是吗
You think?
你的内心声音说了什么
What was your inner voice saying?
他气我毁了气氛
He was mad at me for spoiling the mood.
刚刚气氛的确很不错
It was... it was a really nice mood.
但我内心的声音告诉我
But my... inner voice is telling me that
我们还能回到那种气氛中
I think maybe we can get back there.
你杀了考菲尔德
You killed Caulfield.
我们有证人
We have a witness.
还有对盖勒文的行刺未遂  也是你吗
And the attempt on Galavan-- was that you, too?
-不是时候  -还有霍布斯
- Not now. - And Hobbs.
你把萨斯派去了
You sent Zsasz there?
很复杂  好吗
It's complicated, okay?
搅乱选举对你有什么好处
What does it profit you to mess with the election?
你有自己的肮脏帝国可以统治
You have your own sordid empire to rule over.
走开吧  吉姆
Walk away, Jim.
别管我
Let me be.
哥谭市警局换了领导班子
The GCPD has new leadership.
不再做交易  不再卖人情了
No more deals, no more favors.
如果他们得知是你策划了袭击
If they find out you're behind these attacks,
-我们会全力对你...  -好振奋的演讲
- we will come after you with every... - Rousing speech!
真的
Really!
我都起鸡皮疙瘩了
Goosebumps.
但你是一个人来的  吉姆
But you came here alone, Jim,
没带逮捕令  没带手铐  没带支援  为什么
with no warrant, no cuffs, no backup, and why?
因为你可不希望你的新警监得知
Because you would hate for your new captain to find out
你是如何冷血枪杀了奥格登·巴克
about how you gunned down Ogden Barker in cold blood.
就为收账
Over a debt.
他欠我的账
A debt to me.
他想杀我
He was trying to kill me.
目击证人呢
Where are your witnesses?
就在那前一天  你是不是
And just that day before, I suppose
也没求我把洛布局长赶出哥谭
you did not ask me to run Commissioner Loeb out of town
好让你能官复原职
so that you could get your old job back?
我会面对一切后果
I'll face whatever's coming to me.
我也会
As will I.
再见了  吉姆
Good-bye, Jim.
-还用说  -未必吧
- Obviously. - I don't think so.
-真的  -叫了一下
- I'm serious. - Singed for a second.
别拿死里逃生开玩笑
Hey, you shouldn't be joking about near misses.
下颗子弹可能打进你眼睛里
Next bullet might get stuck right in your eye.
是  长官  不开玩笑
Yes, sir. No joking.
好了  凑过来
All right, gather round.
今天我要给突击队安排首个真正的任务
Today, I'm giving the strike force its first real mission.
立案抓捕哥谭头号公敌
Build a case to put away Gotham's Enemy Number One.
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特/企鹅
该扳倒企鹅了
Time to take down The Penguin.
布鲁斯
Bruce?
塞琳娜  我们走吧
Hey, Selina, come on, let's go.
我不知道你想从布鲁斯少爷这儿得到什么
I don't know what you want with Master Bruce,
但我确定
but I'm certain
没有你  他能过得更好
that his life's gonna be a damn sight better without you in it.
怎么样  红的吗
So, what do you think? Red?
盖勒文
竞选市长
还是蓝的
Or blue?
-红的  -蓝的
- Red. - Blue.
那就蓝的吧
Blue it is.
我想找点乐子
I want some fun.
我受够了在家憋着
I'm sick of staying indoors.
耐心点  芭芭拉  你的机会会来的
Patience, Barbara. Your time will come.
命运之轮在转动了
The wheel is turning.
哥谭市警局忙于抓捕企鹅
While the GCPD chase The Penguin,
我就从他们鼻子底下把市长职位偷走
I'll steal the mayor's office right from under their noses.
你找到她了吗
Did you find her?